## Brwa Hamah Saeed Hamah-Ali

Structural Design and Consulting Engineer
PhD in Structural Engineering at the University of Sulaymaniyah
Senior Lecturer at the University of Sulaymaniyah
ACI, ASCE, ICE, iStructE Student Membership & Graduate member of Iraqi
Engineers Syndicate
brwa.eng@hotmail.com

### Summary

Brwa Hamah Saeed was appointed as lecturer in civil engineering department in July 2022. He accomplished PhD degree in Structural Engineering and seismic retrofitting in March 2022. He is a structural engineering designer for residential and commercial project as freelancer. He is a consultant engineer at Consulting Engineering Bureau. He was also appointed as assistant lecturer in civil department in April 2013. He studied for a master's degree in structural and earthquake engineering with distinction at the University of Sheffield, UK fully funded by HCDP scholar program covered by KRG. Furthermore, he worked as a demonstrator in the department for two years. He also worked as a site engineer for more than two years in wide range of engineering projects. Additionally, he accomplished successfully bachelor degree in building construction ranked at the University of Sulaimani in 2009 and he was ranked as second.

## Experience

#### **Structural Design Engineer and Consultant (Freelance)**

2016-Present

Structural Designing and consulting of high-rise building and engineering projects

#### **Consultant Engineer at Consulting Engineering Bureau**

2016-Present

Structural Designing and consulting

#### Senior Lecturer at the University of Sulaymaniyah

July 2022-Present

Teaching and researching.

#### Junior Lecturer at The University of Sulaymaniyah

April 2013 - 2022

**Teaching Engineering Students** 

#### **Consultant Structural Engineer at Bareaz Group**

February 2014 - February 2015

Structural Designer and Project manager

#### Assistant Engineer at The University of Sulaymaniyah

January 2013 - April 2013

Giving tutorial lab (Concrete Technology and material lab) and Computer program (STAAD). Also,

#### Assistant Researcher at The University of Sulaymaniyah

November 2009 - January 2011

Demonstrator in (Geotechnical, Fluid, Water supply and Material and Concrete Technology) laboratory.

Researcher in Geotechnical and Highway Laboratory for University Consultant Office

#### **Site Engineer at Sanko Company**

July 2009 - September 2010

Road, water tank, Sanitary, Excavation, Survey, retaining wall, Building construction, and Estimation.

Languages

Kurdish

English

Arabic

### Skills & Expertise

Structural Analysis, Structural Engineering, Steel Structures, ETABS, Structural Engineer, Finite Element Analysis, SAP2000, Steel Design, MATLAB, AutoCAD, Civil Engineering, ANSYS, ABAQUS, Numerical Analysis, Surveying, Structural Dynamics, STAAD, Materials, Sustainability, Microsoft Office, Construction Drawings, Earthquake Engineering, Construction, Fluid Mechanics, Project Management, Structural Engineers, Project Estimation GSA, Limit State Geo, Drain 2DX, Drain 3DX.

#### Education

#### The University of Sulaymaniyah

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Structural Engineering, 2016 – 2022

#### The University of Sheffield

Master of Science (MSc), Structural Engineering, 2011 - 2012

Grade: Distinction

#### **Sheffield Hallam University**

TESOL, English Language and Literature, General, 2011 – 2011

#### The University of Sulaymaniyah

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Building and Construction Engineering, 2005 - 2009

Grade: Very Good

### Interests

Lecturing, Structural Consultancy, Structural designing, Project supervision, Project management and researching.

## Personal Details

**Birthday** November 2, 1987

Marital Status Single

# **Contact Information**

00964 (0) 7701581036 brwa.eng@hotmail.com 117Bakhtyari, Sulaymaniyah, Kurdistan Region, Iraq.